He was going to a denied area. A denied
area is a place where CIA people just
can't go, right? But he looks kind of
ethnic and he could fit into, you know,
whatever, the culture.
And so I said, "Buddy, aren't you afraid
of uh like being kidnapped and then we
just never see you again?" And he said,
"Yeah, they offered to implant a a
a chip, a beacon that a ping in my butt
crack." He says. And I said, "Nah, leave
my butt crack alone."
>> Yeah.
Yeah.
That's yeah.
That's fair. I think that's our national
anthem.
>> [laughter]
[snorts]
>> How wary do people have to be of uh
being spied upon today? Do you think
like there's a lot of these new like
data center projects and stuff like that
that's going on with that? Um first
let's talk yeah, real quick about the
data centers. What do you think is
really going on? Because if you look at
the the size of these places,
like we don't need that much data. Like
we're already using our phones. We're
already have like um televisions like
that you know, there's already like a
lot of stuff being stored um on servers.
How are we jumping to a level where we
need that? That's what I want to know.
>> Oh, I have to agree. Besides the fact
that they use massive amounts of water.
And oddly enough, they're located in a
lot of states that don't have a ton of
water, like Texas.
>> Yeah.
>> Or you go out to uh Loudoun County,
Virginia. Okay, we have enough water.
But Loudoun County, Virginia, you drive
for miles and miles and they're just
these never-ending gigantic complexes of
data centers.
>> The proposed Stratus project in Utah is
a massive 40,000 acres in Utah. A 40,000
acre AI data center campus.
Um
>> Two and a half times larger than
Manhattan.
>> Yeah.
I wonder how long the actual data how
big
>> Oh, and and just the data center
requires more than double the current
energy consumption of the entire state
of Utah.
>> Yeah. Come on. I mean, that's
unbelievable. What do you think is
really going on there? Do you have any
intel about it?
>> You have to assume that this is
intel-related because look at the the
companies that are involved. We're
talking about Palantir and Nvidia and
Abraxas, and all these these big
companies that either took CIA
investments to get started as seed
money, or um
or are staffed by retired senior CIA
officers.
They're not doing it for their health.
Why is the C So, is the CIA now is
spying on our own people?
Oh, yeah, that's what Ed Snowden warned
us about. Yeah, without Ed Snowden's
revelations, we wouldn't have any idea
that NSA and CIA were spying on
Americans. Which is not just illegal,
it's a part of NSA's charter that it may
not spy on Americans.
And this place in Utah,
um he and Julian Assange told us about
Utah.
This new compound in Utah that NSA has
built has enough memory storage space
for every phone call, every email, and
every text message from every American
for the next 500 years.
>> Wow.
>> Why?
>> Just that building?
>> Uh-huh.
>> Then why do they need all these
buildings?
>> Yeah, why? They're everywhere.
>> What are they collecting?
>> I'm not sure. And that's the It's like,
what
>> It must be It's got to be all of our
information.
What would you do right now? Is there
any way that people can protect
themselves? Do you know?
>> It's almost impossible now. I I wrote a
series of books during COVID for
Skyhorse Publishing, the CIA Insiders
Guides to surveillance and surveillance
detection, uh lying and lie detection,
and disappearing and living off the
grid. They put them together, and
they're republishing them in the next
month, I guess.
>> Mhm.
>> Um
as one volume, CIA Skills, Tactics, and
The Ultimate Guide to CIA Skills,
Tactics, and Techniques.
>> There we go.
>> But
when it comes to protecting yourself
from from, you know, the data state,
you got to go Eric Rudolph
or Unabomber
and just own no technology at all. It's
the only way to protect yourself.
Otherwise, you're going to be scooped up
in all this. Now, the odd thing is,
according to Ed Snowden, uh
NSA, CIA,
other governmental organizations are
scooping up all this data and they're
just holding it.
Why? Why are they holding it? Now, time
was, really until the immediate
post-9/11 uh
period, where if the government wanted
your information, they had to go to a
federal judge and say, "We want Theo
Von's information and this is the reason
we want it." And the judge had to say,
"Okay, that's a legitimate reason. I'll
sign the warrant."
Now, they just write something called a
national security letter.
They give it to your provider and they
say, "Give us everything you have on
Theo Von." And they just turn it over.
>> Mhm.
>> Or [clears throat] they go to these new
data centers
and uh and just put your name in, your
information, and everything pops up.
They don't even You don't have any legal
protections.
They just take whatever they want.
>> And that's legal now they can do that?
>> And it's legal now.
>> How'd it become legal?
>> In the National Defense Act of of 2016.
National Defense Authorization Act of
2016.
>> Wow.
>> Yeah. Which also, this is a a pet peeve
of mine, that nobody knows about.
It also, for the first time in American
history, allowed the American government
to propagandize the American people.
It was always illegal for our government
to propagandize us.
>> What does it mean?
>> Well, for example, the Voice of America,
that's our government's propaganda news
outlet. And we beam it overseas so
everybody gets the official US point of
view.
Okay.
Back in the in the '80s, the Reagan
administration came up with with these
two broadcasters called uh Radio Martí
and TV Martí to beam at Cuba.
The Cubans try to jam them all the time,
but what they mostly are used for is uh
to broadcast baseball games in Spanish,
which the Cubans love.
>> Got it.
>> I flew down to Cuba to to do a study. I
did a study for the Senate Foreign
Relations Committee when I was the chief
investigator there.
And um
n- Nobody watches TV Martí. You can only
actually get it in the
waiting room of the US Consulate.
>> Got it.
>> So, if you're there to apply for a visa,
you can watch a soap opera on Spanish
that's American propaganda. Nobody
cares.
The radio, people like listening to
baseball.
So,
Dish Network, when it began
when it began selling services in
Florida, found that there was this just
narrow swath along the shore on the on
the west coast of Florida where you
could pick up TV Marti. That's illegal.
You can't propagandize the American
people.
>> Got it.
>> As Americans, we're not allowed to watch
our own government's propaganda.
So, instead of telling Dish Network,
well, you're going to have to like move
your satellite or do something or
pixelate it or whatever,
said, "No, no, no, we'll change the
law."
And so, in the National Defense
Authorization Act of 2016, the Obama
administration said, "No, we can
propagandize Americans now."
>> Wow.
>> And and so, now Radio TV Marti, no
problem.
>> Wow.
>> Yeah.
>> But, I mean, we're always propagandized.
I mean, people put out propaganda all
the time.
>> Yeah. I went to Yemen in 2011
uh when I was with the Senate Foreign
Relations Committee, my fifth trip to
Yemen.
Every time I'd go to Yemen, it's worse
than the previous time.
So, I had a meeting with the defense
attaché.
And he was so proud of this thing that
he was doing, this psyop. I hate that
word. Psyop. I said, "Sure, what's your
what's your psyop?" And he goes, "We're
funding a radio station here modeled on
NPR.
And it plays American jazz.
And then, it has a call-in show so young
Yemeni guys can call in and talk about
the jazz."
I'm like, "What the [__] are you talking
about? That's a terrible idea.
Nobody's going to listen to that." And
nobody did, and they shut it down after
a year.
But, that's that's what we're doing?
>> But, what was the goal of it even?
>> To make people pro-American cuz they
would be like, "Ooh, Americans have
jazz."
>> Oh, I see.
>> So, I'm going to be pro-American now.
It's like, "What are you thinking? You
You sit there and think
>> laundering.
>> Yeah, seriously.
>> That's what it sounds like.
Um
how do I know I can believe you about
anything kind of? People ask you that
all the time?
>> Oh yeah, people ask me all the time.
Um
>> Cuz who would believe anybody that's
ex-CIA? Who would even You know what I'm
saying?
>> Oh, that's such a thing with me.
You know, generally I don't read the
chats.
anywhere, right?
>> Mhm.
>> Everybody I talk to at your level, you,
Tucker Carlson, you know, Patrick
Bet-David, Rogan, whomever, they never
read the chats.
Sometimes I can't help it, and I'll scan
them.
The only time I ever respond is when
people say, "Once CIA, always CIA."
[__] You thought You thought of all of
that all up on your own, huh?
>> Yeah, that's true. That's true.
>> So I said I said to one guy, I said,
"You know what? Let me call Ed Snowden
and the sons of Philip Agee and Ray
McGovern and tell them that you think
they're all still in the CIA."
>> Mhm.
>> So I went to prison for telling the
truth. And
>> That's a good point.
>> I would do it again in a heartbeat. In a
heartbeat.
Nobody else has gone to prison for
ratting out the CIA and its illegal, you
know, programs. I was proud to do it.
>> That's a good answer.
>> Thank you.
>> It's a really good answer. If [laughter]
you really Okay, here it is. I can say
you this. If you really went to jail and
everything, then it's a great answer.
And if you did,
I'll believe you. I believe you. But
also there's a little part of me that's
like, if he didn't, then that's [__]
even colder that he's making it up and
living it. That's the most CIA [__]
>> That would be pretty intense.
>> But that's what I'm saying.
>> Yeah, yeah. No, nobody hate in the world
hates me as much as my ex-wife does.
>> From spending all that time in the CIA
or in jail? At least jail you have a
good excuse.
>> after, but she came every month with the
kids and visited me in jail for 2 years.
[clears throat] Yeah.
>> And so why does she hate you then?
>> Oh no, that's that's all
>> story.
>> post Yeah. I'm actually prohibited by
court order from answering that
question.
>> [laughter]
>> Well, that's I think that's amazing that
she did that and brought her kids to do
it.
>> She was she was great. She was great.
>> A lot of wives I mean I think that's a I
can't even imagine it's a tough thing
for families, especially if you had
young children.
Um
Kudos to her for that.
>> Yeah.
>> Um
Was being in prison kind of fun?
>> [gasps]
>> Um fun.
No.
I No, I wouldn't say fun.
>> Like what was kind of cool about it?
I've always wanted to go to jail.
>> you know there's this old saying that
you don't go to jail to make friends and
I made some lifelong friends in jail. Um
mostly named Gambino, Lucchese, Bonanno,
yeah, Genovese.
>> So a lot of good storytellers in there,
I bet.
>> [gasps]
>> Listen, those guys
were so honorable.
I learned so much from those guys in
just 23 months.
>> Wow.
>> Uh lessons I'll carry with me forever.
Real honor. It's funny, the Italians
were the smallest They they call them
gangs in prison. The Italians weren't a
gang. This is a I'll use the word gang
just for the purpose of this response.
They were the smallest gang in the
prison yet commanded the highest level
of respect.
>> Really? More than the blacks and the
Latinos?
>> The blacks and Latinos were always at at
each other's throats and they had Like
for example, it was Crips and Bloods
and there was this uneasy peace between
them just because it's not worth
upsetting the apple cart and everybody
goes to solitary and gets spread out all
over the country. For the Latinos, it
was far more complicated because it was
Burrachos, Norteños, Latin Kings, MS-13,
um
Mexican Mafia, and then the individual
cartels.
So, overall, there's one gigantic
Hispanic prison gang called Pisces and
then within Pisces are all the different
divisions.
>> Gosh.
>> Yeah, and the Pisces if you were
Hispanic, you were automatically in
Pisces whether you liked it or not and
you had to work out every single day
>> Oh, that's pretty good.
>> for the coming race war with the blacks.
Right. And the whites are like,
"We have nothing to do with this."
>> Yeah, I just want to I would just want
to do it just to get in shape, but
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Sometimes you need motivation.
>> We had we had Aryan Brotherhood
>> What's that? What are they doing? What
are they up to?
>> You know, Aryan Brotherhood of Texas is
far more violent than Aryan Brotherhood,
and they're not It says right there
they're not connected.
I never met anybody from the Aryan
Brotherhood of Texas. Aryan Brotherhood
at a low-security prison
just wants to sort of, you know, go
along to get along.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. You stay out of my way, I'll stay
out of yours. My very first day in
prison, my very first hour in prison
when the when the guard dropped me off
in my cell, the only thing he said to me
the whole time I was, you know, checking
in and getting processed was if
somebody comes into your cell uninvited,
that's an act of aggression. And I said,
"Great. Thank you. I've been here 40
minutes. I'm going to get my ass kicked
now."
Sure enough, as soon as he left, these
two guys walked into my cell, just
walked right in. One of them had a
swastika that took up his entire neck
and then came up onto his face, and the
other one had [__] you tattooed on his
eyelids.
>> Oh, yeah. That check I mean, that's
yeah.
>> And so I jump up, I go, "What do you
want?" Cuz I thought, you know, if I'm
going down, I'm taking one of them down
with me at least. "What do you want?"
And the the one with the swastika, he
says, "You the new guy?" I go, "Yeah,
so?"
>> This is like a This sounds like a story
from like the 1940s, John.
>> Isn't it awful? It It was so I I said in
my second book, "Prison is a combination
of seventh grade, the Lord of the Flies,
and a mental institution, and it's set
in the 1950s."
>> That's hilarious.
>> So I go, "What do you want?" He He goes,
"You the new guy?" I said, "Yeah, so?"
And he goes, I'm standing there like
this. He goes, "You a faggot?" And I go,
"No, I'm not a faggot."
He He says
>> And then we're bummed out?
>> "You a rat?" No, no no gays allowed.
"You a rat?" And I said, "No, I'm not a
rat." "You a chomo?" I go, "I don't know
what that word means.
>> [laughter]
>> He goes, "Chomo, child molester." I
said, "No, I'm not a child molester."
>> That's good.
>> And then he says,
"You can sit with the Aryans in the
cafeteria." And I was like, "Oh,
>> Like
>> Yeah.
>> I guess I'm I'm with the Aryans now.
>> But then a couple of months later simple
rules
>> I was across the hall from from a
captain in the banana family.
And he said to me one day, he goes, "Let
me ask you a question.
Why do you sit with those Nazi retards
every day?"
And I said, "I don't know. I said my
first day here they just told me sit
with them." And he goes, "From today you
are with the Italians."
I said, "It's about time."
>> That was it, yeah.
>> Took you long enough.
>> You got drafted.
>> Yeah. But they were the best.
>> Yeah, but a lot of good stories, dude.
Any good story come to mind from
somebody you like a good story you heard
in uh in prison?
>> Yeah, there's there's one.
I'm actually you're going to think less
of me and I don't care.
>> That's fine. I could tell you some stuff
>> [laughter]
>> that would probably make it even.
>> There was a guy in my housing unit who
was a serial killer.
He was called Truck because he drove
long-distance trucks from East Coast to
West Coast. And he [clears throat] would
pick up prostitutes at uh
truck stops and he would rape them and
murder them. Drive them a couple of
hundred miles down the highway and then
dump the bodies out. So,
the cops estimated that he killed 14. It
was probably more than that. But um he
strangled one and she survived. And she
was able to give the cops the license
number. Now, this was in the days before
DNA training DNA testing. So,
this guy
>> Before DNA testing.
>> was in the '70s.
>> Oh, he'd been in for a long time.
>> Got it. So, um
for reasons that were never clear to me,
this guy constantly sought my approval.
He was full of [__] He would come up he
had the worst breath cuz he had just
these blackened rotten nubs where his
where that used to be his teeth. And he
was saying
>> [__] dick soft, dude.
>> awful. Awful. He goes, "You CIA?" And I
said, "Yeah, I used to be." He goes, "I
did work for the CIA. I ran a shrimp
boat full of weapons to Angola." I go,
"Get the [__] out of here." I didn't
know he was a serial killer. I go, "Get
the [__] out of here. A shrimp boat to
Angola. Have you ever been on a shrimp
boat?" And I walked away.
People are looking at me like, "Are you
crazy? Do you know who that is?" Well, I
didn't know who it was.
So, um
instead of making him mad, it just made
him more actively seek my approval. Mhm.
So, I'm a big Pittsburgh Steelers fan.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> And um
he would say, "Hey John, the Steelers
are the game of the featured game of the
week. I saved you a seat in the TV
room." I'm like, "Oh, thanks, Chuck."
I'm like, "Okay." "John, uh I I know you
listen to classic rock. There's a new
classic rock station 1600 a.m. You
should check it out." I'm like, "Okay,
thanks, Chuck."
In the meantime,
there's this guy we called Cat in the
Hat cuz he had this oddly elongated
head, like a birth defect, kind of giant
Cat in the Hat head.
And he comes up to me one day and he
said, "Hey, I heard you had a an empty
bunk in your in your cell. I want to
move into your cell. I heard it's a good
cell." And I said, "Well, not so fast,
buddy." I said, "We don't have any
pedophiles in our cell, and no rats." I
said, "What's your crime?" He goes,
"Murder for hire." And no
I don't even care about that. But the
other guy I can't speak for the other
guys.
>> Yeah, I was trying to like I was trying
to be part of the group, you know? But
go on. Go on.
>> [laughter]
>> So, uh
so he says um
I in murder for hire. I said, "I don't
think I like that any better than the
pedophiles or the rats. What what were
the circumstances?" And he said, "I owed
the mob a lot of money, 100,000 in
gambling. I couldn't pay it. So, I took
out a life insurance policy on my
business partner and I hired a hitman to
kill him and and the hitman got uh got
caught." I said, "Mhm, let me think
about it." Well, think about it. I went
straight to the law library and I looked
up his case. And that wasn't it at all.
It was true. He owed the mob 100,000. He
took out the life insurance policy. He
hired the hitman.
He got caught cuz of course he's going
to get caught. Where the Where's the
first place the cops are going to go?
Where the money went. And he ratted out
the hitman so that he wouldn't get the
federal death penalty. Instead he got 20
years.
>> Oh.
>> So, I said, "No rats in the room."
So,
he was mad at me.
Anyway, one day Jake Tapper comes up to
the prison to interview me. And I get
called down to the lieutenant's office.
Normally, if you're called down to the
lieutenant's office,
it's to go to solitary. If you come
back, usually it's cuz you ratted
somebody out. Well, I went down there to
sign the the waiver so I could give Jake
Tapper the interview.
So, I'm sitting in the TV room next to
Truck.
Truck was very, very sensitive about
being called a chomo cuz that girl that
he strangled was 16, which technically
made him a chomo. Right, right?
So,
Truck's sitting here, I'm sitting here.
Right here is Cat in the Hat with his
back toward me.
He's on the computer. There's like this
internal internet, not internet,
internal email system. He doesn't see
me. I'm sitting 18 inches away from him.
And then he says to the guy next to him,
"Do you hear? Kiriakou got called down
to the lieutenant's office." He goes,
"That guy's a [__] rat. He went down
there to rat us out." And I just sat
there watching the game. And then Truck
says,
"That [__] guy just called you a
rat."
And I said,
"An hour ago I heard him call you a
chomo."
Which was a total lie. I just made it
up.
He didn't say a single word. He just
stood up, walked over here, and beat
this guy almost to death.
They had to land a helicopter in the
yard to life-flight Cat in the Hat to
Pittsburgh.
They gave Truck five more years, and
Cat's
>> [clears throat]
>> Cat in the Hat, huh?
>> Yeah, it's Cat in the Hat. See,
now how come I didn't think of that? Cuz
I'm not a comedian. I should have put
that in my book.
>> I don't know. Is there any real value in
me thinking of that? That's a good
question. I don't know.
>> Six weeks later, Cat in the Hat is
finally released from the hospital. He
comes, he's all [__] up still.
And um and he's like this. Somebody had
told him what had happened. He He goes,
"I I wanted to say I'm sorry for calling
you a rat. I should never have said
that."
And everybody is stops to look to see
what I'm going to say. Well, what am I
going to say? Uh, forget it. It's all
water under the bridge. I go, "Listen,
look at me. Look at me." And he lifts
his head up. And I said, "So help me
God, if I ever hear my name cross your
lips ever again, you're dead. And they
won't even find you."
"Oh, I'm sorry. I'm sorry."
So, everybody's like, "Huh."
The CIA guy's tough after all.
But I said in the book, one of my rules
that I learned at the CIA, let others do
your dirty work. And then I get called
down to the lieutenant's office again.
Because as he's beating him, I sat back
down. I'm watching the game. Everybody
else runs. As soon as there's a fight,
everybody just runs like cockroaches.
>> though, man.
>> Right? So, I'm watching the game.
"Kiriakou, lieutenant's office,
immediately." They always do it the same
way. It's like a They're They're
caricatures of themselves.
>> Mhm.
>> So, I go down there.
And the one of the lieutenants, there's
two of them, and he says, "So, tell us
about this fight."
And I go, "What fight?"
"What fight? You're going to be a smart
guy now?" I said, "I don't know what the
[__] you're talking about."
"The fight. We had four cameras
showing you saying something to that
crazy person, and then he got up and
beat the other guy." I said, "I was
watching the Steelers game. I don't know
what you're talking about."
"Oh, you're not going to tell us about
the fight." I said, "You know what?
Maybe I will tell you about the fight.
Maybe it was you that started the fight.
Did you ever think of that? Maybe it
wasn't me. I was an innocent bystander.
Maybe you put them up to fight each
other. I think I might make a complaint
against you." He goes, "Get the [__] out
of my office."
And I wrote in my book,
rule number one,
admit nothing, deny everything, make
counter accusations. And as I was
walking out, I just said, "Exactly."
>> Dang, bro. I don't even know what to
think anymore.
>> You know, I figured
>> Sometimes that's where you get people to
that point. You're like, this you know,
it's like
>> me and pushed me and pushed me. And at
sentencing, the judge sentenced me to a
minimum security work camp. And the CIA
was furious that I got such a light
sentence and I was going to minimum
security camp. So, the CIA intervened to
send me to a media sorry a low security
prison, which is an actual prison with
the double walls and
>> They were furious that the CIA was. When
I was first charged
I mean, this is a potential death
penalty case. Three counts of espionage
for talking to ABC News and the New York
Times.
>> Cuz you were talking to them about about
torture, right?
What case is specific were you talking
to them about?
>> Abu Zubaydah.
And they were furious because nobody had
ever confirmed that there was a torture
program.
And I said it was illegal. Besides being
immoral and unethical, it's illegal. You
want to torture people? God bless. But
you got to change the law first. We're a
nation of laws.
>> Which countries you think had the most
the like the toughest torture programs
over the years?
Or do you even know?
>> Over the years, you like let's go back a
hundred years.
The Chinese, the Vietnamese, and the
Belgians.
The Belgians, if you can imagine the
horrors that they perpetrated in Congo.
It of of epic proportions.
Um
Yeah, the Russians, the Iranians, the
Israelis, the United States.
>> Is it weird like cuz we talk about the
term terrorism now, but it's like it
definitely feels like when you talked
about it a few a little bit of earlier,
it's like it feels sometimes it's like
how much is America like a terrorist
state in the world? And I hate to say
that because this is the country that we
live in, but it's like I think at a
certain point if you use
it you know, I don't know. I don't know,
you know, it's got to be hard to figure
that out. But it's like um
you know, it's like when do you use like
fear tactics and and that sort of thing
to make sure that everything's okay, you
know?
Um
Yeah, I don't know. It's like
do you Here's my question. Do you think
it's possible for America to get to a
place uh
where or an actual peacekeeper? Or do
you think it's possible to keep peace
without terror?
Did I make any sense or not?
>> Yeah, that's a hard question.
>> Good.
>> You know, and and I think my answer has
changed over the years.
I believed for a very long time that we
were the good guys. I was a true
believer. That's why I worked there. We
were the good guys.
>> And we still I think as people we still
are. As people as citizens we still are.
>> Agreed. We still are. Somebody commented
on a Facebook post that I made the other
day.
Like uh I heard you say that the United
States is the best country in the world.
You should be ashamed of yourself. I was
like, I believe that the United States
is the best country in the world. That's
why I live here. I could go live in some
other country if I wanted to, but this
is the best country in the world. We
have problems. Every country has
problems. But the reason why I'm as
active and as vocal as I am is because I
want to change the things that I
disagree with.
I don't think we should be a nation that
tortures people or murders people
without trial. If somebody is a clear
and present danger, which is the
language that's used in the amendment to
12333.
Okay.
Clear and present danger. They're
getting ready to you know, deliver the
dirty bomb or you know, whatever. Okay.
Sometimes we have to work in the
shadows. Awful, but it but it's a fact
of life. But if you just send teams
around the world to kill people whose
politics you don't like.
People who have never been charged with
a crime. Then shame on us. That's not
what the founding fathers gave us.
So if you want to torture people, you
got to change the law. Ronald Reagan
said
we were a shining city on a hill, right?
We were a beacon of hope for human
rights and civil rights and civil
liberties. That's the country I want to
be.
>> Same.
That's what most people want to be.
>> Exactly.
>> Do you think we can get back to that
place or what do you think?
>> I think it's possible.
>> You do?
>> I think it's going to take a very long
time, but I think it's possible.
>> Mhm.
>> And I think we have to start by
by trying to snap out of this mindset
that we have to be the world's
policeman.
Yeah, like why?
I have relatives in Greece and friends
all over Europe and they ask me the same
question all the time. Why are you guys
doing this?
Like like did [clears throat] we really
need to overthrow Libya?
Uh
Gaddafi rather in Libya? Of course not.
>> of people are don't know what's going
on. They just want their families to be
okay. They don't want data centers. A
lot of people do not want AI.
[clears throat] They don't give a [__]
about it. It's not going to benefit
them.
>> frightened.
>> Oh, the Pope is frightened. I'm trying
to get the Pope to come and
offered that I would go to the Vatican
and talk with the Pope. I just want to I
want to learn about what he thinks.
>> Yeah.
The Archbishop of the Greek Orthodox
Church just issued an encyclical 100%
supporting everything the Pope said on
this.
>> Wow.
>> Mhm.
>> Yeah, I mean it would be a blessing to
get to talk with him and just learn. I
just want to like be able to like, you
know, share a message, be a part of like
not me share it, but just be like you
know, just part of the telephone game of
of helping or being a part of the
message getting out if I can.
>> Yeah.
>> Cuz I do think it's important. We don't
want that. Nobody wants it. 30 people
want it. 100 people want it with a lot
of power.
>> Exactly.
>> want it.
Yes.
>> Nobody wants it. I Nobody wants it.
>> Yeah, there it is right there.
>> Nobody wants an encyclical.
>> Yeah. I read about this. I've read part
of the Pope's, but I haven't seen this
new one. This is from the Orthodox
Church?
>> Yeah, the Greek Orthodox Archbishop,
it's Elpidophoros is his name, endorsing
everything the Pope said about AI.
>> Um you have a new podcast.
>> Yeah, thanks Sean for hanging out. Sorry
if I haven't had the best questions at
certain points.
>> No, your questions were great and they
cut right to the heart of things.
>> Trying to get my brain back on track a
little bit. It's just been like a long
month, but um before you do leave, I
know you have a podcast that you're
starting your own finally. Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> been on You've been on all of them, so
you have to start your own. And it's
called The Briefing Room?
>> John Kiriakou's Briefing Room.
>> We're going to launch it in about 4
weeks.
Um if you go to realjohnkiriakou on
YouTube, it'll pop up saying coming
soon. Please, please, please subscribe.
And I have another one, too,
called John Kiriakou's Dead Drop, that's
on Apple Podcast and Spotify. It's just
story after story after story. And it's
it's been actually very popular. Been
very lucky. We've gone up to number five
in the history category worldwide.
>> Oh, it's exciting.
>> Yeah, very exciting.
>> Yeah. It's an exciting time. I mean,
that's one thing that we also have to
remember is like, sure, things seem this
way and that way, but also it is an
like, if you can see excitement as like
being of all things
and not just things that seem positive,
but things that could seem um
to be decided, then there is a lot of
excitement. And so, that's like a nice
way to think about things.
>> Agreed.
>> Um and you did Did your book, The
Ultimate Guide to CIA Skills, Tactics,
and Techniques. Is there a basic one you
can give us out of the book, man, that's
just something that you can notice about
people when you
>> Yeah. The one I the the part that I'm
proudest of in this book is the section
on surveillance and surveillance
detection. I took it so seriously that I
actually became a surveillance
instructor at the CIA for the last 2
years that I was at headquarters. Um
I'll tell you
something that happened to me when I was
in Pakistan.
I was always very, very, very careful
about my own personal security. And um
I noticed one day
I was staying at a at a guest house, a
little 14-room guest house.
And uh I noticed one day there's a guy
in a motorcycle. He's trying really hard
to stay in my blind spot. And the only
reason I even noticed him was he had a
red motorcycle helmet on. And nobody in
Pakistan wore motorcycle helmets. I
don't even know where you would buy a
motorcycle helmet.
So, I was like, "Huh, that's funny." I
speed up, he speeds up. I slow down, he
slows down. I change lanes, he changes
lanes. I'm like, "Oh, this this isn't
good." I get to the entrance to the
diplomatic quarter, which was the part
of town where all the embassies were,
and he breaks off.
Well, I work like 14, 15, 16 hours every
single day. I get to work when it's
dark, I leave work when it's dark. And
so I pull out of the diplomatic quarter
and the guy's on me again. And I was
like, "Oh, this is
definitely not good." I was worried
about it all night.
So the next morning I get up at 5:00 in
the morning and I'm taking a different
route to work every day. I'm leaving at
a different time every day. My routes to
work don't make any sense.
Just to make sure I'm not being
followed. And now twice I am being
followed. There's a definition of
surveillance at the CIA. It's multiple
sightings at time and distance. So you
see the person more than once at
different times of the day and at
different places.
So
we have a database. So I put in the
database when I first arrived, I think
I'm under surveillance. It's a
motorcycle. Here's the license number.
This is a description of the guy. He's
wearing a red helmet.
Next day I get up at 5:00 in the
morning. I just open the door a crack. I
look up and down the street. I don't see
anybody.
So they they had assigned us these like
poles, these retracting poles with a
mirror on the bottom. So I look under my
car. I don't see any explosives or
tracking devices or anything. So you got
to be careful, you know. So I get in the
car. I go like two blocks and the guy's
on me again.
So I finally get to the office
and um I waited for the security officer
to come in and I said, "Listen, I'm
under surveillance. I'm 100% sure I'm
under surveillance." I told him about
the three sightings. He's like, "Ooh,
this isn't good." I said, "I know." He
said, "We have to wait until the chief
comes in."
So finally the chief comes in around
7:00
and I said, "I'm under surveillance.
100% certain."
So I explained to him the three
different sightings.
And he's like,
>> [sighs and gasps]
>> "Well,
you know what you have to do." And I
said, "I I know."
He goes, "You never popped your cherry
that way, did you?"
>> I shoot somebody?
>> Uh-huh. And I said, "Nope, never needed
to."
He's like, "Well, we're going to have
we're going to have teams out there.
Don't worry. We're going to have guys
all around you. You're not going to be
alone." I'm like, "Okay, all right." I
was very worried. So So back to my
office. My office it was me, I was the
only staff officer, and six retirees who
had all been in the senior intelligence
service. Every one of the six had either
been the chief or deputy chief of Near
Eastern operations. One had been the
assistant deputy director of the CIA.
But they all came back after 9/11 for
patriotic reasons. But if you're a
contractor, you can't be the chief. So
they all worked for me, right?
And word got around they're like, "Don't
worry, buddy. We're all going to be out
there. Don't worry about a thing." I'm
like, "I'm very worried."
That afternoon, I have a meeting at a
safe house that we shared with the
Pakistani intelligence service.
We interrogated a prisoner. And I get up
to leave,
and I don't know what possessed me to
stop. And I turned and I said, "General
Muhammad,
are you following me?"
And he says, "No. Why?"
I said, "Because I'm under surveillance.
I'm 100% sure that I'm under
surveillance, and I'm going to kill the
guy this afternoon."
And he's like, "No, it's not us."
I never saw him again.
So weeks later,
we heard that a bunch of them were
sitting around the table,
and one of them said, "The new guy,
Kiriakou,
he's a nice guy." And everybody's like,
"Yeah, he's a very nice guy." And then
one of them said, "You know what?
Nobody's that nice.
He's probably being nice just to to
trick us
into a sense of complacency. We don't
know what he's doing when he's not here.
He's probably spying on us."
I wasn't.
But they put the worst surveillance
officer in the entire Pakistani
intelligence service on me. So instead
of two blocks back, he's right there in
my blind spot. And it was only because I
stopped before I got to the door that
afternoon and asked General Muhammad
if they were following me,
that's the only reason that guy's not in
the ground today.
I was going to kill him that afternoon.
>> Oh, yes, I was.
>> Dang, John, about to pop off, bro.
>> convinced he was going to kill me.
>> guy.
>> Mhm.
>> That's crazy, bro.
>> [laughter]
>> Dang, dude. I think everybody wants to
shoot somebody.
But they don't let you. I worked with a
guy, great friend, go to the same
church, run the same men's group. They
don't let you.
>> And he's a psychiatrist.
>> [laughter]
>> Sorry. You made me laugh. He's a
psychiatrist. And he said to me,
"I find it fascinating
that you don't have PTSD."
And I said, "Is that good or bad?" He
said, "From a psychiatric point of
view?" And I said, "Yeah." He goes,
"Not good." Mhm.
I said, "I wasn't afraid of those
people, Steve.
I was not afraid of them."
>> Yeah, it is interesting, man, the things
that we hold, what's going on inside of
us, you know? How it comes out, what
gets figured out, you know?
>> You just never know. You never know
what's going to bother you. You never
know what's going to stick in your mind
and bother you and fester for years. It
happens.
>> Yeah.
The stories, man.
And about just making a story, you know?
I mean, you seem like a kind of guy that
likes to make a story, you know?
>> I like telling these stories. And people
say,
>> You're living a story, though, I mean.
>> Oh, yeah, yeah. Oh, listen, I'm an
adrenaline junkie. I don't know what I
would do if I didn't have these stories
in my past. I'd be like, "Oh my god." My
first wife, she's like, "I want to move
back to Ohio and I want you to sell car
insurance with my cousin Dean." I said,
"I would rather cut my throat than move
to Ohio and sell insurance with your
cousin Dean." I'd rather join the Aryan
Brotherhood in prison.
>> Seriously. Seriously.
>> Wait, and you did?
>> And I did.
>> So, I think a lot of
insurance next time.
>> Yeah, next life.
>> John, tell [clears throat] your son I
said, "What's up?" that you mentioned on
the way in.
>> Thank you, Max. Max